<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml>
    <poem>
        <meta coder="edm" codedWhen="2021-08-23"/>
    <title>Leaves</title>
    <author>Lloyd Schwartz - 1941-</author>
    <num para="1">1</num>
    <para n="1">Every <month>October</month> it becomes important, no, necessary to see the leaves
        turning, to be surrounded by leaves turning; it's not just the symbolism, to confront in the
            <mortality>death</mortality> of the year your <mortality>death</mortality>, one blazing
        farewell appearance, though the irony isn't lost on you that nature is most seductive when
        it's about to <mortality>die</mortality>, flaunting the dazzle of its incipient exit, an
        ending that at least so far the effects of human progress (pollution, acid rain) have not
        yet frightened you enough to make you believe is real; that is, you know this ending is a
        deception because of course nature is always renewing itself— the trees don't die, they just
        pretend, go out in style, and return in style: a new style.</para>
    <num para="2">2</num>
    <para n="2"> Is it deliberate how far they make you go especially if you live in the <city>city</city> to get
        far enough away from home to see not just <nature>trees</nature> but only trees? The boring <city>highways</city>,
        <city>roadsigns</city>, <city>high speeds</city>, <city>10-axle trucks</city> passing you as if they were in an even greater hurry
        than you to look at <nature>leaves</nature>: so you drive in terror for literal hours and it looks like <sky>rain</sky>,
        or <sky>snow</sky>, but it's probably just <sky>clouds</sky> (too <sky>cloudy</sky> to see any color?) and you wonder, given
        the poverty of your memory, which <city>road</city> had the most color last year, but it doesn't matter
        since <mortality>you're probably too late anyway, or too early</mortality>— whichever road you take will be the
        wrong one and you've probably come all this way for nothing.</para>
    <num para="3">3</num>
    <para n="3">You'll be driving along depressed when suddenly a <sky>cloud</sky> will move and the <sky>sun</sky> will
        muscle through and ignite the hills. It may not last. Probably won't last. But for a moment
        the whole world comes to. Wakes up. Proves it lives. It lives— <color>red</color>, <color>yellow</color>, <color>orange</color>, <color>brown</color>,
        <color>russet</color>, <color>ocher</color>, <color>vermilion</color>, <color>gold</color>. <fire>Flame</fire> and rust. <fire>Flame</fire> and rust, the permutations of <fire>burning</fire>.
        You're on <fire>fire</fire>. Your eyes are on <fire>fire</fire>. It won't last, you don't want it to last. You can't
        stand any more. But you don't want it to stop. It's what you've come for. It's what you'll
        come back for. It won't stay with you, but you'll remember that it felt like nothing else
        you've felt or something you've felt that also didn't last.</para>
    </poem>
</xml>
